（忆往昔）
你干了什么
What's your sin?
我是个糟糕透顶的母亲
I was a horrible mother.
你是在无耻地巴结我 以期我放了你
You are shamelessly sucking up so that I'll free you.
你好再次去胡作非为 给我捣乱
so you can run amok and gum up my operation once again.
你还剩谁可以信任
Who is there left for you to trust?
我们很像
You and I are very much alike.
但我没杀我弟弟
Yeah, except I didn't kill my brother.
血印能被转移到配得上它的人身上
The mark can be transferred to someone who's worthy.
但你得先答应我一件事
But make me a promise first.
当我呼唤你时 用刀杀了我
When I call you, use the blade on me.
你不觉得如果该隐知道怎么去除血印
Don't you think that if Cain knew how to remove the mark,
他几个世纪之前就会做了吗
he would have done it, like, centuries ago?
我不想再纠结于治愈方法了 萨姆
I'm done trying to find a cure, Sammy.
小卡就快成功了
Cass is so close.
小卡也只是可能能从该隐那儿查到什么
Maybe Cass is onto something with Cain …
但答案不在外面
But the answer is not out there.
答案就是我
It's with me.
所以在力竭之前 我会继续抗争
So, I'm gonna fight it till I can't fight it anymore.
（如今）
5分钟后熄灯
Lights out in five.
有信吗
Hey, any mail?
就一般那些
Oh, the usual…
反死刑人士的贺卡
Postcards from anti-penalty folk,
你仰慕者的求婚信
proposals from your lady admirers.
你不说你不搭理她们了吗
You said you were done with those.
你妻子怎么样了 阿曼达
Hey, how's your wife, by the way… Amanda?
是叫这个吧
That's her name, isn't it?
你知道我杀过一个阿曼达吗
You know I killed an Amanda once?
第四个
My fourth.
我愿一样伺候你老婆 伙计
I'd do your wife the same, buddy,
不过要慢点
Only slower.
两周后的周二 汤米
Two weeks from Tuesday, Tommy.
嗯
Yeah.
来吧
Let's do it!
这就来吧
Let's do it now!
托里弗又骚扰你了
Tolliver giving you the usual grief?
没什么新鲜的
Nothing new.
简直等不及他死了
I can't wait till he's gone.
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
你怎么进来的
How'd you get in here?!
我这辈子用过很多名字
I've gone by many names in this life.
其中之一是谋杀之父
The father of murder is one of them.
根据政府计算
And by the state's count,
你夺走了六条生命 汤米
you've taken six lives yourself, Tommy.
但据我计算 是九条
Although by my count, it's nine.
得了
Oh, come on.
你不是那种
You aren't one of those.
不承认的家伙吧
"It wasn't me" type fellas, are you?
因为我知道你是个杀人凶手
Because I know you're a killer,
跟我一样
just like me.
是啊 是我做的
Yeah, I did it.
诚实
Honesty.
这很好
That's good.
要的就是这个劲
That's the spirit!
你肯定想知道我来做什么
Now, I bet you're wondering what I'm doing here.
我是来惩罚你 还是来救你的
Did I come to punish you or save you?
这个嘛
Well…
其实 汤米
The truth is, Tommy…
两者都有
I'm here to do both.
[邪恶力量 第10季第14集]
（德克萨斯州 西利文斯顿 波兰斯基监狱）
- 十二宫杀手 - 7名被害人
- The Zodiac. - Seven victims.
- 达默 - 17个
- Dahmer? - 17.
真是吓人啊 简直是你的另一面
That's some freaky stuff, man. It's a whole new side of you.
这叫真实案例 迪恩 是个爱好
It's called true crime, Dean. It's a hobby.
不 钓鲈鱼 针绣花边 这才叫爱好
No. Bass fishing, needlepoint… that's a hobby, okay?
收集连环杀手的趣闻
Collecting serial-killer stats…
这是有病
that's… that is an illness.
- 拿证件 - 嗯
- Get your badge. - Yeah.
先生们 请陈述来访事宜
Hello, gentlemen. State the nature of your visit.
我们是检察长办公室的
From the office of the inspector general.
跟典狱长有约
Got an appointment with the warden.
谢谢 左边停车
Thank you. Parking is to the left.
请停在访客停车位
Look for visitor parking only.
那么这个消失大师是怎么回事
All right, so what are the stats on this, uh, vanishing act here?
汤米·托里弗 09年被判犯下六宗谋杀
Tommy Tolliver was convicted of six murders back in '09,
但那只是能定罪的
but those are just the ones that stuck.
据报道
According to the news,
他逃出了死囚区的囚室
he escaped from a locked cell on death row,
完全无法解释 胡迪尼一样地逃脱了
this inexplicable, Houdini-esque escape.
怎么回事
So what are we thinking?
魔术师连环杀手吗
Some sort of a mass-murdering magician?
或者会瞬移的恶魔
Yeah, or a teleporting demon.
或者鬼知道还有什么能闯进重刑监狱的高墙
or a who knows what that can walk through supermax walls.
或许是我们的案子
Could be in our wheelhouse.
是你的癖好
Yeah, your wheelhouse.
还「爱好」呢
"Hobby."
斯基夫典狱长
Warden Skeiff?
莫尔和罗纳尔多检察员
Uh, inspectors Moore and Ranaldo.
我们通过电话
We spoke on the phone.
嗯 欢迎来到死囚区
Yeah. Welcome to death row.
看看吧
Have a look.
你们不会发现任何违规之处
But good luck finding anything out of TDCJ compliance.
跟我说说到底怎么回事吧
So, why don't you tell me what happened?
托里弗消失那晚
The night Tolliver disappeared,
我们监狱的管理还是一如既往得严格
our little ship was running as tight as ever,
我有相关文件可以证明
and I got documentation to prove it.
你是否承认媒体的说法
Do you stand by what the press is saying…
囚室紧锁 没有安全漏洞
Locked cell, no security breach,
狱警无违规行为
no guard misconduct?
哪家媒体
Which press?
主流媒体要唯我是问
Mainstream media is calling for my head,
说我严重失职
said I was grossly incompetent.
但小报说
But the tabloids, they're saying…
说是魔法
They're saying it's magic.
汤米施展黑暗法术逃脱升天
that Tommy pulled off some dark miracle to escape.
莫非你相信吗
You saying you believe that?
我认为昨晚的确有魔法师到场
I'm saying there was some kind of magician on the block last night,
但不是汤米
but it wasn't Tommy.
这就在托里弗消失之前
That's right before Tolliver vanished.
灯火管制吗
Was that a brownout?
我也以为是 但随后…
That was my thought, but then…
是狱警吗
Is it one of the guards?
不是
Nope.
我不知道他是谁 怎么进来的
But I don't know who he is, how he got in,
或是怎么把托里弗弄出去的
or how he and Tolliver got out.
能放大吗
Can you zoom in on that?
能 放大过了
Can and have.
太暗 看不清什么
Too dark to make out much of anything.
放大
Do it.
停
Freeze it.
放大
Blow it up.
不接吗
Gonna answer that?
现在不用
Not at this moment.
你在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
我说了 我不知道他在哪
I told you, I don't know where he is.
我和该隐又不是朋友
Me and Cain ain't friends.
他猎杀恶魔
He kills demons.
我这种小喽啰躲得远远的
Low-level guys like me keep our distance.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
好吧
All right!
All right.
有人见过他 就这几个月
He's been seen, past few months,
穿过博格沼泽
making passes through Bogg's Marsh,
离这里一个郡
one county over.
没人知道为什么 他要做什么
No one knows why, what for.
我说了 我们会躲得远远的
Like I said, we keep our distance.
你就知道这么多
And that's all you know.
对
Yes.
对 我发誓
Yes, I swear.
好吧
Okay.
上一季86个 我只拿了48个的积分
86 last quarter, while I only get credit for 48.
我几乎每次收魂都跟阿尔班一起合作的
A-and I was working with Alban on nearly all of those soul jobs.
如果你10秒内不快点说到点子上
If you don't arrive at a point within the next 10 seconds,
我发誓 我一定…
so help me, I'll…
作为十字路口恶魔
As a crossroads demon,
我收集灵魂得到的积分
I have received less credit than I am due.
少于我应得的
for soul collections…
陛下
…my king.
你是想升职吗
So you're looking for a promotion?
不 我只求…
No. I'm just asking…
我只是想凭我与阿尔班
I'm merely suggesting that I get credit.
合作的工作得到积分
for the work that I did beside Alban.
工作量相等 绩效也应该相等
Equal credit for equal work.
好吧 给你积分
Fine. You can have your credit.
- 谢谢 - 这小子
- Thank you. - The wee man! Ugh!
母亲 您有什么意见
Mother, you have, uh, an opinion.
想跟大家说吗
you'd like to share with the room?
没有
Oh, no.
只是个人想法
Private thought,
不该打扰你 或宫廷事务
nothing to do with you or the affairs of the court.
只是换了我就不这么做
It's just not what I would do.
那说说啊 换了你会怎么做
Oh, enlighten us all. What would you do?
这个恶魔要求你给他和另一人
This demon asks you to equalize credit.
合作的工作给相同的积分
for his and another's work…
可以说是分孩子
Split the baby, if you will.
要是我 就真分孩子
Well then I would well and truly split the baby.
我会把这个唧唧歪歪 可怜巴巴
I'd cut this puling, pathetic,
贪心不足的饭桶撕成两半
greed-grubbing git in two,
真撕成两半
literally,
然后把他血淋淋的尸首挂在宫门外
then I'd nail his bloody halves to the doors of the court…
提醒别人少来浪费陛下的时间
A reminder to all not to waste the king's time.
抱怨的人只会越来越多
Whiners beget whiners.
你不能鼓励这样的行为
You can't reward behavior like that…
你小时候要糖我什么时候随你了
Why I never gave in when you asked for sweeties as a child,
不管你哭得多惨
no matter how much you cried.
你那时候…
Well, you were a very…
很胖嘛 亲爱的
chunky child, darling.
有点太肥了
Bit of a bloater.
够了
That's enough.
怎么做 陛下
What'll it be, sir?
我们…
Let's do…
照她说的办
What she said.
什么…
Wha…
不不
N-no, no, no!
不要啊
No, no, no, no!
这才是我的好儿子
That's my boy.
怎么样
So?
小卡还是不接
Cass is still not answering.
这可好 我一直在查汤米·托里弗
Great. Well, I have been looking into Tommy Tolliver,
想看看能不能搞明白
seeing if I can figure out.
该隐为什么要救他出去
why Cain went to the trouble of springing him.
怎么样
And?
还是不明白
Still pretty unclear.
我找到了奥兰多的一份档案
I did find this blotter out of Orlando.
是他爸 里昂·托里弗的
about his dad, Leon Tolliver.
有其子必有其父
Uh, like father, like son.
他是重罪犯 还有袭击罪的新通缉令
Convicted felon, fresh warrant for an assault charge,
但他失踪了 已经消失几周了
but he's gone missing, hasn't been seen in a week.
你觉得两者有联系吗
You think the two are connected?
警方以为他只是畏罪潜逃
I mean, the police just assumed he fled the warrant,
但如果汤米是该隐带走的 那可能不是巧合了
but if Cain took Tommy, it might not be a coincidence.
怎么 该隐对他们家都有仇吗
So, what, Cain's got a vendetta against the entire family?
或许吧
Maybe.
是小卡
It's Cass.
你哪呢
Hey, where you at?
伊利诺伊州
Illinois.
小卡 我们有线索了
Hey, Cass, we got a lead.
该隐绑架了德州一名死刑犯
Cain abducted a Texas death row inmate.
名叫汤米·托里弗
named Tommy Tolliver.
- 他死了 - 什么
- He's dead. - What?
你怎么知道
How do you know?
算是合理推论吧
Call it an educated guess.
该隐一直在忙活
Cain has been very busy.
你在哪 我们去找你
Okay, where are you? We'll come to you.
我再打来
I'll call you back.
你好 卡西迪奥
Hello, Castiel.
你做了什么
What have you yone?
这些死人吗
These bodies?
只是在清理我很早以前留下的烂摊子
Just cleaning up a mess I made a long time ago.
该隐 我知道你曾是什么
Cain, I know what you were.
但你长久以来一直克制住了
But you'd resisted for so long.
没办法
What can I say?
我又恢复旧瘾了
I got the taste back.
阿比顿的军队追着我不放
With Abaddon's army gunning for me,
我只得重拾武器
I had to take up arms again,
我喜欢那种感觉
and I liked how it felt.
那些是恶魔
Those were demons.
这些
These…
是人类
Humans.
血印渴求各种生灵
Eh, the mark thirsts for all kinds.
这是屠杀
This is a massacre.
是的
Yes.
很快 就将成为种族屠杀
And soon it'll be a genocide.
我的后人 我繁衍出的麻烦
My children, my whole poisoned issue.
很多还逍遥在外
A lot of them out there right now…
杀人犯 凶徒 贼
Killers, fighters, thieves,
有些相对平静一些
Some more peaceful than others.
但他们还带着那份疾病
But they still carry it… the disease.
如果血印嗜血 我就给它我的血脉
If the mark wants blood, I'll give it mine.
你要把他们都杀了
You'll kill them all?
你是亚当和夏娃的长子
You are Adam and Eve's firstborn.
你的后人数不胜数
Your descendents are legion.
我至多也就杀个十分之一吧
At most, I'm culling…1 in 10.
所有人的十分之一
Of everyone.
我有的是时间
I've got time.
迪恩怎么样了
How's Dean, by the way?
听说他干得不错 杀了阿比顿
I hear he did good, took Abaddon down.
他情况不妙
He's not well.
即便第一刃已经藏了起来
Even with the first blade hidden,
迪恩依然在渐渐向血印屈服
Dean is losing his fight against the mark.
如果我们不找到办法解决
If we don't find a cure…
没有解决之道
There is no cure.
我就是活生生的例子
I'm living proof of that.
不过别担心迪恩
But don't worry about Dean.
我早晚会去找他的
I'll get to him, in due time.
抱歉 卡西迪奥
Sorry, Castiel.
你不在我的名单上
You're not on my list.
克劳力
Crowley…
今天很漫长 你一定累了
Long day. I'm sure you must be tired.
但我有个小想法
But I've had a wee idea.
什么
Yes?
你应该不熟悉奥莉薇特
The name Olivette means little to you.
她是大巫师团的高层人物
A high-ranking member of the grand coven,
指控我的那个人
the one who led the charge against me.
其实 就是私仇 我不否认
Really, it's a grudge. I won't even deny it.
但她刚刚来到了美国
But she's just come back to the states,
我想 陛下能不能 发发慈悲
and I thought if you, in your kingly beneficence,
好心帮帮我
would be so kind as to assist me,
现在出击正合适
now would be an excellent time to strike.
厉害啊 母亲
Well done, mother.
下次你想放长线骗人
Next time you run a long con,
多等几小时
let more than a few hours of suspicious,
按兵不动
entirely uncharacteristic usefulness pass.
再提出请求
before making your ask.
你以为我有别的动机吗
You think I had an ulterior motive,
你以为我在摆布你吗
that I've been manipulating you?
简直司马昭之心
You couldn't be more transparent.
拜托
Well, duh!
我当然在摆布你
Of course I was manipulating you!
我可是你母亲
I am your mother, after all.
我们就是喜欢操纵他人
Manipulation's who we are.
我的小香肠
My wee sausage,
我有别的动机又如何
what matter is it that I had a motive?
我们今天很开心 不是吗
We had fun today, didn't we?
还好吧
It was fine.
我们可以更开心的
We could have more.
离开这破地方
Get out of this dump,
离开这些恶心的谄媚者
A break from these foul-smelling suck-ups,
去真实世界活动一下筋骨
flex our muscles in the real world.
同时干掉一个讨厌的老巫婆
and in the process take out a miserable, old witch.
她已经跟我作对几个世纪了
who's been standing in my way for centuries.
怎么样
What do you say?
抱歉我没能带来更好的消息 迪恩
I'm sorry I couldn't bring better news, Dean.
不怪你 小卡
It's not your fault, Cass.
谢谢
Thank you.
警长又告诉我了一些名字
All right, the sheriff gave me a few more names,
初步核实了一些尸体的身份
some preliminary I.D.s on the bodies.
- 怎么样 - 似乎与小卡的说法吻合
- And? - And it seems to fit Cass' story.
显然是无从得知他们与该隐的关系了
I mean, there's no way to tell the relation to Cain, obviously,
但他在挨个家族的灭族
but he's wiping out entire families, one after another.
下一个是谁 他灭完托里弗家族了吗
So who's next? Is he done with the Tollivers?
应该是的
Uh, I think so.
里昂没有
I mean, Leon didn't have.
兄弟姐妹或其他孩子
any siblings or any other children I can see,
汤米又没结过婚
and Tommy was never married, so I…
拜托 该死
Oh, come on. Damn it.
怎么了
What?
汤米真有个孩子 早已疏远
Tommy did have a son, estranged,
跟妈妈住在俄亥俄州
who lives with his mother in Ohio,
奥斯汀·雷诺兹 12岁
Uh, Austin Reynolds, 12 years old.
孩子还活着吗
Is the kid still alive?
一小时前还活着
As of an hour ago, yeah.
他还更新了状态
He updated his status.
拜托 这是个孩子啊
But, I mean, come on. It's a kid.
你不会认为该隐真会…
You don't really think Cain would…
他会的
Yes, he would.
那些坟墓里有老人 萨姆 还有女人
There were old men in those graves, Sam, women.
你也听到小卡说的了
I mean, you heard Cass.
大清仓 所有人都得死
It's a fire sale. Everyone must go.
你去哪
Where you going?
我们知道该隐会去哪
We know where Cain's gonna be.
那孩子有危险啊
The kid's in danger.
那我们追踪他去俄亥俄州 然后呢
Okay, so what, we track him down to Ohio, and then what?
做我该做的
Then I'll do what I have to do.
我要杀了该隐
I'll kill Cain.
他给我血印时
When he gave me the mark,
该隐就说会有这一天
Cain said that this day would come,
我杀了阿比顿之后
That after I killed Abaddon,
我得去杀他
I would have to come and put him down.
好啊 那么你是在听一个疯子的
Great. So you're taking orders from a madman.
不 他当时并不疯
No, he wasn't mad then.
该隐成功抗拒血印很长的时间
Cain resisted the mark for a long time,
然后我来了 非要去找第一刃
then I came, kicking up trouble about the blade.
是我害他走上这条路 这怪我
I sent him down this path. This is on me.
那不代表非得是你去找他
It doesn't mean you have to be the one to go after him.
当然得是我 只有一样东西能杀了他
Yes, it does. And there's only one thing that can kill him.
第一刃
The blade.
迪恩说得对
Dean's right.
迪恩 用第一刃去对付该隐
Dean, wielding the blade against Cain himself…
不管输赢
…win or lose,
你可能再也无法恢复了
you may never come back from that fight.
我知道
I know.
我需要一支恶魔小队 好穿过她的警戒线
I'll need a demon force to get us past her security.
两个10人小组应该就够了
2 units of 10 should suffice.
等我们进去
Once we're inside,
我们要让她措手不及
we'll want to throw her off guard,
搅乱她的思绪
mess with her head a little bit.
所以我想 用苋菜魔文
So I thought… rune of amaranth.
幻觉 高招
Illusion work. Smart.
失陪 我就来
Excuse me. I'll be right back.
哎呦呦 这不是…
Well, well, well, if it isn't…
该隐回来了
Cain's back.
他黑化了 我需要第一刃
He's gone dark, and I need the blade.
我为什么要给你
Why would I do that for you?
因为你也很希望
Because you have as much reason.
该隐死掉
to want Cain off the board as anyone.
该隐有张杀戮名单 你在上面
Cain has a kill list, and you're on it.
怎么样 克劳力 同意吗
What do you say, Crowley? You in?
好
Yes.
很好 我短信告诉你地点
Good. I'll text you the location.
打乱她的阵脚之后
Once she's well flustered,
我有个特别狠的咒语可以了结她
I've got an especially nasty spell to finish her off with.
母亲 没戏了
Mother, it's not happening.
- 什么 - 今天不行
- What? - Not today.
- 你去哪 - 临时有事
- Where are you going? - Something's come up.
奥莉薇特不急 这事急
Olivette can wait. This can't.
那是我想的那个吗
Is that what I think it is?!
这和你无关
Not that it's any of your business.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你要把它送给你的小伙伴 那个姓温的
Bringing it to your wee pal, the Winchester boy.
你要把这个给一个
You'd give that to the one person.
能够使用其力量对付你的人
who can harness its power against you.
他对你来说是威胁
He's a threat to you!
我们有共同的敌人 更大的威胁
We've a common enemy, a bigger threat.
即使他不对你的生命构成威胁
Well, if he's not a threat to your life,
也绝对对你的公信力有损
he's certainly a threat to your credibility.
我们讨论过这对你的声誉有什么影响
We've talked about what this does to your reputation.
我不想跟你吵
We are not having this conversation.
和猎人交结
Consorting with hunters!
我的天
Oh, me. Oh, my.
你还真觉得他们是你的朋友
You honestly believe that they're your friends,
他们在乎你
that they care about you?!
孩子在这里
Kid here?
就在附近
He's nearby.
在谷仓楼上
Upstairs in the barn.
正在玩篮球
He's playing with a basketball.
该隐很快就会来
Cain will strike soon.
也许今晚 也许明天 但快了
Maybe tonight, maybe tomorrow, but soon.
- 等他来了… - 我知道
- And when he does … - Yeah, I got it.
你独自拿刀去对付他
You charge in with the blade solo.
孩子呢
And the kid?
我们就看着等着 直到该隐发起攻击
What, we just watch and wait until Cain attacks?
我以为这是营救任务呢
I thought this was a rescue mission.
该隐出现后我们救下孩子
We save the kid after Cain shows.
我们知道该隐要什么 这是我们唯一的优势
We know what Cain's after. That's our only advantage.
我们想困住该隐 我们就利用它
We want to trap Cain, we use it.
一个12岁的诱饵
A 12-year-old as bait.
真不敢相信你们
I can't believe what I'm hearing.
我也是
Neither can I.
怎么了 克劳力
What's the matter, Crowley?
你突然有了良知
You suddenly grow a conscience?
不愿让小孩子犯险吗
Too good to put a minor in danger?
一点都不在乎那孩子
Don't give a damn about the kid.
我说的是对我们的风险
I'm talking about the risk to us.
没有我们
There is no us.
你来这里只有一个原因 就是把刀给我
You're here for one reason. That's to hand me the blade.
对 关于这事
Yeah, about that.
既然这事是要成为
Seeing as this is shaping up to be one of those,
先抓再杀的两步行动
two-step capture then kill kind of deals,
我觉得你的小伙伴们都会同意
I think your buddies would agree.
你最好不要拿到第一刃
it's better to keep the blade out of your hands.
直到我们完全困住该隐
until we've got Cain sewn up,
安全起见
just to be safe.
现在 再说说你们的计划
Now, back to this plan of yours.
那么
So…
如果这能成功 我们抓住了该隐
If this works and we capture Cain,
然后呢
then what?
船到桥头
We'll cross that bridge when we c…
自然直
if we come to it.
你知道上周
You know last week,
我说到时候我虽败犹荣
when I said that I would go down swinging when the time came?
我的意思是我能安然接受
I meant that I was at peace with that.
我只是没有意识到会来得这么快
I just didn't realize the time would come so soon,
就现在
you know, like right now.
我害怕 萨姆
I'm scared, Sam.
有人吗
Someone there?
你好 奥斯汀
Hello, Austin.
你在这里干什么
What are you doing here?
我是来杀你的
I'm here to kill you.
不 你不会
No, you won't.
快跑
Run!
你没法阻止我
You can't stop me.
不要
Don't.
求你了 不要
Please don't.
幻觉咒语
Illusion spell.
是啊 真正的奥斯汀早就走了
Oh, yeah. The real Austin is long gone.
18世纪的魔法
18th-century magic.
如果要我猜 苋菜魔文
If I had to hazard a guess, rune of amaranth.
好眼力
Good eye.
从我母亲那里拿来的
Something I picked up from my mother.
我知道你们害怕我
Well, I know you fear me.
那么应该…
I can only assume…
聪明
Clever.
这困不住我很久
Won't hold me for long, you know.
不需要
It won't need to.
小卡 你还好吗
Cass, hey, you okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
成功了吗
It worked?
是的
Yeah.
该我了
My turn.
迪恩 听着 我们想帮忙
Dean, look, we want to help.
不
No.
你们去 只会添麻烦
No, with you in the ring, it'd just be a liability.
- 迪恩 - 我会太担心他会对你们做什么
- Dean? - I'd be too worried about what he could do to you…
或是我会做什么
Or what I could.
再说 我需要你们三个人在外面
Plus, I need you three out here.
解决从里面走出来的不管什么东西
to take out whatever comes out of there.
我是认真的 不管是什么东西
And I'm serious. I mean whatever comes out.
乐意效劳
Happily.
我怎么确保你用完会还给我
What guarantee do I have that you'll give it back when you're done?
如果我活下来 走出那里
If I survive and I come out of there.
却不还给你
and I don't give it back,
你们就有个更大的麻烦了
you'll all have a much bigger problem on your hands.
迪恩
Dean?
我没事
I'm good.
你好 迪恩
Hello, Dean.
不知道说什么好了吗 孩子
At a loss for words, my son?
那我说吧
Allow me.
现在你该对我说 为时不晚
This is the part where you tell me it's not too late.
我可以放下武器
and I can lay down arms,
放弃使命
abandon my mission.
「我们没必要打」
"We don't have to fight""
那些客套话就免了
I'll spare us the formalities.
已经没法跟你讲理了
You're past talking down.
该隐 你已经完全疯了
Cain, you're fully mental.
我倒认为我终于想清楚了
Oh, I prefer to think I've finally gotten clear.
我和路西法做交易
When I made my bargain with Lucifer,
杀了亚伯时
killed Abel,
我在地球上制造了一个污点
I released a stain upon the earth,
一个比我更深 更长久的污点
a stain deeper and far more lasting than mere precedence.
你的血脉被污染了 这是你的说法
Your bloodline's tainted, so you say.
我确定
So I know.
不是所有的杀手都是我的后代
Not all killers are my descendants,
我的后代不都是杀手
and not all my descendants are killers,
但是的够多了
but enough are,
多到让我明白消灭他们
enough for me to know that extinguishing them.
是我至少该为这世界做的
is the least I owe this world.
你真能说 少了汤米 里昂这样的人
Can you honestly tell me that humanity's not better off.
世界不会更好吗
with fewer Tommys and fewer Leons…
或是你这样的人
Fewer yous?
那个孩子呢
And what about the kid?
他将来可好可坏
He could go either way.
我喜欢做得彻底点
I prefer to be thorough.
感觉如何 迪恩 再次握着刀
How's it feel, Dean, holding the blade again?
感觉是达到目的的方式
It feels like a means to an end.
那就动手吧
Then do it.
这比我预期中你持刃该有的力量要弱啊
That seems a bit weaker than I would expect from you with the blade.
我觉得你可以做得更好
I think you can do better.
除非
Unless…
你有所保留
You're holding back.
怎么了 迪恩
What is it, Dean?
你觉得如果你能控制得住 你就不会被压垮
Do you think if you hold back just enough, you won't succumb,
你就能像进来时一样离开吗
that you'll leave this fight the same as you entered?!
看看我的样子吧 孩子
Look to my example, boy!
血印和刀都是无法被抵抗的
There is no resisting the mark or the blade.
只有缓解和复发
There is only remission and relapse!
你告诉过我 这一天会来到
You told me that this day would come.
你告诉过我 我有一天得杀了你
You told me that I would have to kill you.
是这样吗
Is that so?
恐怕 你误会了我的意图 迪恩
I'm afraid you've misunderstood my intentions here, Dean.
你的宠物小天使发现了我坟场时
When your pet angel found my burial site,
我考虑过像打苍蝇一样打死他
I thought about ending him and swatting him like a fly.
但我随后又想到了你
But then I thought about you.
你最大的弱点
Your biggest weakness,
从我认识你时就注意到了
the thing I noticed the moment I met you,
你的勇气 你不计后果的蛮勇
your courage, your reckless bravado.
我让他走了
I let him go,
我知道他会向你汇报
knowing that he would report back to you,
我知道你会带着唯一
knowing you would bring into battle.
能杀死我的东西来战斗
the one thing that can kill me,
唯一一件我真正想要的东西
the one thing I truly want.
已经太久了
Oh, it's been too long.
那种熟悉的感觉让我怀疑
That old feeling makes me wonder.
我曾经怎么会有力量抵抗它
how I ever had the strength to resist.
鉴于我即将对你做的事
This may be hard to believe.
这也许会很难相信
in light of what I'm about to do to you,
但是我在乎你 迪恩
but I care about you, dean.
我真的在乎
I truly do.
但我知道我是在帮你的忙
But I know I'm doing you a favor.
我在救你
I'm saving you.
救我什么
Saving me from what?
摆脱你的命运
From your fate.
你就从没想到过
Has it never occurred to you?
你就从没考虑过
Have you never mused upon the fact.
你活在和我相反的命运之中
that you're living my life in reverse?
我的故事从我杀死我弟弟开始
My story began when I killed my brother,
你的故事不可避免地 将以此结束
and that's where your story inevitably will end.
不 从没想过
No. Never.
这叫做该隐的血印是有原因的
It's called the mark of Cain for a reason!
首先 你会杀了克劳力
First … first, you'd kill Crowley.
这事上 你会有奇怪复杂的情绪
There'd be some strange, mixed feelings on that one,
但你会有你的理由
but you'd have your reason.
你会杀了他 毫无悔恨
You'd get it done, no remorse.
然后你会杀了那个天使 卡西迪奥
And then you'd kill the angel, Castiel.
那一个
Now, that one …
我怀疑会造成可怕的伤害
that I suspect would hurt something awful.
然后
And then!
然后就是将彻底摧毁你的谋杀
Then would come the murder you'd never survive,
最终将把你变成一个狂徒
the one that would finally turn you into.
就像我当初那样
as much of a savage as it did me.
- 不 - 你的弟弟 萨姆
- No. - Your brother, Sam.
唯一阻挡在你和那命运之间的
The only thing standing between you and that destiny.
就是第一刃
is this blade.
不客气 孩子
You're welcome, my son.
怎么了
What's the matter?
告诉我 我不必这么做
Tell me I don't have to do this.
告诉我 你会停手
Tell me that you'll stop.
告诉我 你能停下
Tell me that you can stop!
我永远不会停下
I will never stop.
迪恩
Dean?
迪恩 第一刃呢
Dean, the blade.
你骗了我
You lied to me.
不是今天第一次了
It's not the first time today.
该隐的名单 你不在其中
Cain's list … you weren't on it.
你做到了
You did it.
迪恩 你做到了
Dean, you did it.
费格斯
Fergus…
我不想听什么「早告诉你了」 现在不想
I don't want to hear it, the "I told you so"s, not now.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你以为呢 我要离开
What's it look like? I'm leaving.
又想摆布我
Another petty manipulation.
不
No.
那是什么 母亲 你想从我这里得到什么
Then what, mother? What do you want from me?!
你不明白我的失望
You can't understand my disappointment…
或是骄傲
Or my pride.
你并不知道
You don't know this,
但我离开你后 在我被迫离开你之后
but after I left you, after I was forced to leave you,
我听说你死了 你的肉体死了
I heard of your death … your mortal death.
我以为我从此失去了你
I thought you were gone to me forever.
然后 数百年之后
Then, hundreds of years later.
数千里之外
and thousands of miles away,
我找到了你 地狱之王
I find you, the king of hell,
不是运气 不是偶然
and not by luck or accident.
是你自己实现了这一切
You made that happen all by yourself.
你不是母亲
You're not a mother.
你不会了解那种骄傲的感觉
You can't know what that pride felt like,
不知道这有多重大
how huge it was.
但你能为了我 努力设想一下吗
But can you try to imagine, for me?
你现在是否明白 看到你变成
Now do you understand why it breaks my heart.
这样的笨蛋让我多么伤心
to see what a colossal numb nut you've become?!
你得到了王冠
You've got the crown,
但你却不是个真正的统治者
but you're no ruler, not really!
一个坐在王座上 可悲 无聊的小孩子
A sad, bored, wee boy on the throne.
那对巴不得你死掉的猎人
who'll flop ass-up the second those Winchesters …
温家兄弟 一开口找你 你就会立刻
hunters who'd as soon see you dead as have you to tea …
招之即来
ask you to.
你如今已经不是王了
You're no king, not anymore.
你是他们的走狗
You're their bitch.
迪恩 你之前所做的
Dean, um, you know, what you did back there,
非常了不起
it was incredible.
如果你能不迷失自己而这么做
You know, if you can do that without losing yourself,
那就有希望 甚至都不需要治愈办法
that's cause for hope, even without a cure.
是啊
Yeah.
也许吧
Maybe.
第一刃在哪
So, where's the blade?
安全的地方
Somewhere safe.
很好
Good.
失陪了
Well, if you guys will excuse me,
我想去睡上四天
I think I am gonna go sleep for about four days.
当然
Of course.
他还好吗
How is he?
- 萨姆 - 小卡
- Sam? - Cass…
迪恩有麻烦了
Dean's in trouble.